CURRICULUM VITAE

IYAYA PHANUEL MAKHAKHA

CONTACT INFORMATION

Address: P.O BOX 41422-00100 Nairobi, Kenya.

Cell Phone: +254725891717

E-mail: phanueliyaya.pi@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 5th March 1997.

Identity Number: 33706255

Gender: Male

Citizenship: Kenyan

PROFILE

I'm a knowledgeable and thorough Information Technology student, well acquainted with the IT infrastructure. I have almost 2 years of experience in repairing computer hardware, diagnosing and resolving network and software issues. Driven and self motivated and therefore effective at completing tasks with minimal supervision. Confident leader and enthusiastic communicator. Certified in Computer networks and Network Security.

OBJECTIVES

To develop my skills in an organization or institution that offers both challenge as well as opportunity for personal initiative and career advancement leading up to a position of responsibility as a result of giving service to the society with remarkable performance.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2015 Bachelor of Science Information Technology (BSc. I.T)

Institution; Dedan Kimathi University of Technology.

2011-2014 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

School; St. Anthony Boys High School, Kitale.

Grade; A- (79 points)

2008-2010 Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (KCPE)

School; St. Paul Thomas Academy, Murang'a.

Grade; A- (386 Marks)

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE 1 (CCNA 1)
- CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE 2 (CCNA 2)
- FORTINET NETWORK SECURITY EXPERT

Certificate; NSE 1

NSE 2

- WEB DEVELOPMENT (Graphic design, Web Design)
- INTERNET OF THINGS (Skills for All)
- NETWORKING BASICS
- INTRODUCTION TO CYBER SECURITY (CISCO)
- INITIAL NETWORK DEVICES AND CONFIGURATIONS(CISCO)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Hardware

- Assembly
- Maintenance
- Peripherals
- Printers
- Drivers
- Trouble shooting

Software

- Installation
- Debugging
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Outlook
- Windows installation and maintenance

Operating Systems

- Microsoft Windows
- Linux
- Google Chrome

Networks

- Configuration
- Troubleshooting
- Routers
- Servers
- LAN/WAN Technology
- security

Security

- Networking Security
- Virus protection
- Maintenance
- Monitoring
- Backup Management

Programming Languages

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap

GENERAL SKILLS

- Communication
- Problem solving
- Leadership
- Teamwork

TRAINING

- Fortinet Network Security Training.
- Cisco Training.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

(2021) Maintenance, Installation and sales of Electronics **Otomart Supermarket**Mutalia

(2020) ICT Technical Support at Nairobi Centre for International Arbitration, Nairobi

(2019) Web Designing

(2017-2018) Microsoft Office trainer

(2015-2016) Cyber Manager at Rimaya Cyber, Bungoma.

LANGUAGES

Am fluent in both Speaking and writing the following languages;

- i. English
- ii. Kiswahili

HOBBIES

- Volunteering / Community Involvement
- Reading
- Blogging
- Web Designing
- Sports

REFERENCE

Arnold Cheloti Ndukuyu, Head of ICT, Nairobi Centre for International Arbitration.

P.O. Box 548-00200 Nairobi, Kenya. Tel. 0722942376